Inventory of the Calfee Papers 1812-1919, 1859-1889
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Calfee Papers 1812-1919, 1859-1889
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Mss. 39.1 C15
431 items.
Papers and letters, chiefly 1858-1889, of the Calfee family of southwest Virginia.
Calvin J. Calfee ,; David H. Calfee ,; James Calfee ,; L. S. Calfee ,; William B. Calfee.
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
Purchased: 431 items, 07/02/1938.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, chiefly 1858-1889, of the Calfee family of southwest Virginia. Includes letters written from Texas by Calvin J. Calfee and letters written by Confederate soldiers David H. Calfee, James Calfee, L. S. Calfee and William B. Calfee as well as deeds for land in Pulaski and Wythe counties, Virginia.
Arrangement
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into series, then alphebetically by person's name, and finally chronologically by date.
Organization
This collection has been organized into 4 series:
1. Correspondence
2. Vouchers
3. Legal Papers
4. Other Papers.
Index Terms
Family Names:
Calfee family.
Persons:
Calfee, Calvin J.; Calfee, David H.; Calfee, James.; Calfee, L. S.; Calfee, William B.
Subjects:
Wythe County (Virginia)--History--19th century.; Pulaski County (Virginia)--History--19th century.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; Texas--History--1846-1950.
Contents List
  Series 1: Correspondence
- Correspondence, 1858-1919., items. (Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence between family members, 1858-1919., 97 items. (Folder 1)
    Correspondence between members of the Calfee family of southwest Virginia.
  - Correspondence during the Civil War, 1861-1865., 26 items. (Folder 2)
    Correspondence of the Calfee family of southwest Virginia, describing conditions during the Civil War.
    - James Calfee, at Raleigh Court House, Virginia, to his brother, L. S. Calfee, 19 May 1861., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - James Calfee, Raleigh County, Virginia, to L. S. Calfee, 9 June 1861., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - J. C. Honaker, Berkeley County, [Virginia], to his mother, [ ? ] Honaker, 23 June 1861., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - David H. Calfee, at Camp Lee near Richmond, to his father, James D. Calfee, 5 Aug. 1861., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - Sarah A. Calfee, at Barren Spring, Wythe County, Virginia, to her brother, D. H. Calfee, 7 Aug. 1861., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - David H. Calfee, at White Sulphur, Greenbrier County, Virginia, to his brother, [ ] Calfee, 13 Aug. 1861., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - [ ? ) [Calfee], in Camp at Meadow Bluff, Greenhrier County, Virginia, to his uncle and aunt, 29 Sept. 1861., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - John Calfee, at Abbs Valley, [Tazewell County, Virginia], to James D. Calfee, 28 Oct. 1861., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - James Calfee, in camp near Bowling Green, Ky., to his wife, [ ? ] Calfee, 7 Jan. 1862., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - William B. Calfee, in camp near Hensonvill, to his father, [ ? ] Calfee, 15 April 1862., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - John Calfee, at Abbs Valley, [Tazewell County, Virginia], to his brother, James D. Calfee, 2 July 1862., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - William B. Calfee, at Camp Pound Cap, to his father, [ ? ] Calfee, 9 Sept. 1862., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - William B. Calfee, in camp near Wytheville, [Virginia], to his father, [ ? ] Calfee, 12 Nov. 1862., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - L. S. Calfee, Prince George County, Virginia, to his uncle and aunt, 28 Dec. 1862., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - John Calfee, at Abbs Valley, [Tazewell County, Virginia], to his brother, James D. Calfee, 21 April 1863., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - William B. Calfee, in camp near Knoxville, Tennesse, to his aunt, [ ? ], 25 May 1863., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - William B. Calfee, in camp near Knoxville, Tennesse, to his father, [ ? ] Calfee, 29 May 1863., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - William B. Calfee, in camp near Loudon, Roane County, Tennesse, to his father, [ ? ] Calfee, 13 June 1863., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - William B. Calfee, in camp near Knoxville, Tennesse, to his sister, Mary A. Calfee, 13 July 1863., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - John Calfee, at Abbs Valley, [Tazewell County, Virginia], to his brother, Davis [Calfee?], 23 July 1863., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - William B. Calfee, at Strawberry Plains, [Tennesse], to his sister, Mary A. Calfee, at Drapers Valley, Pulaski County, Virginia, 1 Aug. 1863., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - John Calfee, at Abbs Valley, [Tazewell County, Virginia], to James [Calfee?], 8 Oct. 1863., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - William B. Calfee, in camp near Dalton, Ga., to his father, [ ? ] Calfee, 1 Dec. 1863., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - L. S. Calfee, in camp near Dalton, Ga., to his brother, [ ? ] Calfee, 9 Dec. 1863., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - William B. Calfee, at Kingston Hospital, near Atlanta, Ga., to his father, [ ? ] Calfee, 24 June 1864., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - [ ? ], at Headquarters, Pine Grove, to [ ? ], 30 Aug. 1865., 1 item. (Folder 2)
  - Correspondence from Calvin J. Calfee of Texas to his brother, Leander S. Calfee, 1859-1861., 10 items. (Folder 2)
    - Calvin J. Calfee, Sycamore Creek, Tarrant County, Texas to his brother, Leander S. Calfee, 18 April 1859., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - Calvin J. Calfee, Fort Worth, Texas to his brother, Leander S. Calfee, 17 July 1859., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - Calvin J. Calfee, Goliad, Texas to his brother, Leander S. Calfee, 19 Feb. 1860., 1 item. Incomplete. (Folder 2)
    - Calvin J. Calfee, Goliad, Texas to his brother, Leander S. Calfee, 21 May 1860., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - Calvin J. Calfee, Goliad, Texas to his brother, Leander S. Calfee, 11 Nov. 1860., 1 item. Incomplete. (Folder 2)
    - Calvin J. Calfee, Goliad, Texas to his brother, Leander S. Calfee, 24 Jan. 1861., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - Calvin J. Calfee, Goliad, Texas to his brother, Leander S. Calfee, 14 Feb. 1861., 1 item. Incomplete. (Folder 2)
    - Calvin J. Calfee, Goliad, Texas to his brother, Leander S. Calfee, 31 March 1861., 1 item. (Folder 2)
    - Calvin J. Calfee, Goliad, Texas to his brother, Leander S. Calfee, 7 April 1861., 1 item. Incomplete. (Folder 2)
    - Calvin J. Calfee, Goliad, Texas to his brother, Leander S. Calfee, 12 May 1861., 1 item. (Folder 2)
  - Calvin J. Calfee, Goliad, Texas to his aunt, Rhoda Calfee, Wythe County, Virginia, 25 Nov. 1860., 1 item. (Folder 2)
  Series 2: Vouchers
- Vouchers, including invoices, notes, and tax bills, 1845-1913. (Folder 3)
  - Bailey (Joannah C.), 1853-1889., 6 items. (Folder 3)
  - Bailey (Leonard G.), 1849-1890., 27 items. (Folder 3)
  - Calfee (J. D.), 1870-1884., 18 items. (Folder 3)
  - Calfee (J. L.), 1884-1900., 8 items. (Folder 3)
  - Calfee (James), 1898-1901., 9 items. (Folder 3)
  - Calfee (James D.), 1845-1901., 42 items. (Folder 3)
  - Calfee (James L.), 1892-1899., 5 items. (Folder 3)
  - Calfee (R. T.), 1898-1913., 12 items. (Folder 3)
  - Calfee (Sallie), 1896-1904., 5 items. (Folder 3)
  - Calfee (W. B.), 1885-1894., 4 items. (Folder 3)
  - Calfee (W. B.) & Brother, 1890-1901., 48 items. (Folder 4)
  - Calfee (W. W.), 1914-1919., 4 items. (Folder 4)
  - Calfee (William) estate, 1823-1870., 3 items. (Folder 4)
  - Cassell (Joana), 1844-1890., 8 items. (Folder 4)
  - Other members of the Calfee family, 1820-1915., 23 items. (Folder 4)
  - Other persons, 1864-1882., 12 items. (Folder 4)
  Series 3: Legal Papers
- Legal Papers, 1812-1892., 14 items. (Folder 5)
  - A court order changing the location of a public road in Wythe County, Virginia, 1812., 1 item. (Folder 5)
  - A court order establishing rates for James Calfee's ferry across New River, 1817., 1 item. (Folder 5)
  - A deed given by Samuel T. Calfee and wife to James D. Calfee covering a half interest in a tract of land in Wythe County, Virginia, 1846., 1 item. (Folder 5)
  - A deed given by Susan S. Davis granting to James D. Calfee her claim upon a tract of land in Wythe County, Virginia, 1852., 1 item. (Folder 5)
  - A deed given by Samuel T. Calfee and wife to Henry Honaker, Sr., covering a tract of land in Wythe County, Virginia, 1853., 1 item. (Folder 5)
  - A written guarentee of a wheat fan sold by Benton F. Peters to Leonard G. Bailey, 1856., 1 item. (Folder 5)
  - A bond given by Leonard G. Bailey and wife to James D. Calfee guaranteeing a good deed to a tract of land in Wythe County, Virginia, 1856., 1 item. (Folder 5)
  - A deed given by James D. Calfee to William R. Wheeler covering a tract of land in Wythe and Pulaski Counties, Virginia, 1871., 1 item. (Folder 5)
  - Suit in Carroll County of Irven Ayers vs. John Quesenberry, 1873., 1 item. (Folder 5)
  - A deed given by James D. Calfee to William R. Wheeler covering a tract of land in Wythe and Pulaski Counties, Virginia, 1882., 1 item. (Folder 5)
  - An order from the commissioner of accounts for an inventory of the personal property of J. D. Calfee, 1885., 1 item. 2 copies. (Folder 5)
  - A deed given by D. P. Graham and wife and John W. Robinson and wife to James L. Calfee, covering a tract of land in Wythe County, Virginia, 1892., 1 item. (Folder 5)
  Series 4: Other Papers
- Other Papers, 1865, n.d., 51 items. (Folder 5)
  - Furlough of Private 0. P. Simmons, 1865., 1 item. (Folder 5)
  - Instructions for weaving and needle work, n.d., 2 items. (Folder 5)
  - Prescription for a cough remedy, n.d., 1 item. (Folder 5)
  - Verses and newspaper clippings, n.d., 8 items. 3 NCL. (Folder 5)
  - A memorandum book, n.d., 1 item. (Folder 5)
  - Printed advertising sheets, n.d., 5 items. (Folder 5)
  - Other papers, n.d., 12 items. (Folder 5)
  - Unidentified pieces and fragments, n.d., 11 items. (Folder 5)
  - Envelopes and covers, n.d., 10 items. (Folder 5)